<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Engineering in the Digital Age on Saleh Toodarvari Articles</title>
    <link>https://saleh-ato.github.io/blog/en/tags/engineering-in-the-digital-age/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Engineering in the Digital Age on Saleh Toodarvari Articles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 14:00:36 +0330</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://saleh-ato.github.io/blog/en/tags/engineering-in-the-digital-age/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Will AI Replace Engineers? Navigating the Future of Engineering in the Age of Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://saleh-ato.github.io/blog/en/posts/will-ai-replace-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 14:00:36 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://saleh-ato.github.io/blog/en/posts/will-ai-replace-engineers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rapid advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AI) has sparked debates across various industries, particularly in engineering. As AI technologies evolve, questions arise: Will AI replace engineers? Or will it transform the role of engineers, enhancing their capabilities and productivity? This article delves into the impact of AI on the engineering profession, exploring both the challenges and opportunities it presents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-ai-in-engineering&#34;&gt;The Rise of AI in Engineering&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI&amp;rsquo;s integration into engineering is not a distant future—it&amp;rsquo;s happening now. From automating repetitive tasks to optimizing design processes, AI is reshaping how engineers approach their work. Tools like generative design software and AI-driven simulation platforms are enabling engineers to explore a multitude of design possibilities quickly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
